Guide to the Gabriel A. Almond Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gabriel A. Almond papers
1939-2002
SC0339
Almond, Gabriel A. (Gabriel Abraham), 1911-2002
29 Linear feet (38 boxes)
The papers include correspondence, minutes, memoranda, reports, conference materials, and other items pertaining to Almond's academic career, 1964-1986; organizations represented include the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Political Science Association, the National Academy of Sciences, and the Social Science Research Council. Later additions to the papers include correspondence, 1964-2001; manuscripts, typescripts and reprints, 1946-1986; and lecture notes and research files.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Gabriel Almond, 1986, and the estate of Gabriel Almond, 2002-2003.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Gabriel Almond received his bachelor's, master's and Ph.D. (1938) degrees from the University of Chicago, and taught at Yale (1949-1951, 1959-1963) and Princeton (1951-1959), before joining the Stanford faculty as executive head of the Department of Political Science in 1963. The following year he became chairman of the executive committee of the Institute of Political Studies, and became professor emeritus in 1976. A distinguished internationalist, he taught at universities in Japan and Brazil, and in 1972-1973 he was an overseas fellow at Cambridge University. In 1965-1966 he was president of the American Political Science Association. During his career he was a frequent consultant to the Department of State and other policy-making bodies of the government.
Description of the Collection
Papers in the first accession (accession 1986-047) accession include correspondence, minutes, memoranda, reports, conference materials, and other papers pertaining to his academic career, 1964-1986; organizations represented include the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Political Science Association, the National Academy of Sciences, and the Social Science Research Council. Papers in the 2002-254 accession include correspondence, 1939-1961, and 1984-2001; lecture notes from the 1970s-1980s; a small group of speeches, 1964-1991; and correspondence, papers and other materials from a project on fundamentalism, sponsored by the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1987-1997. Papers in the 2003-017 accession (1946-1985) include correspondence, text of talks and articles, publication contracts and accounts, reprints and book reviews, research files, and other materials.
Access Terms
Almond, Gabriel A. (Gabriel Abraham), 1911-2002; American Academy of Arts and Sciences.; American Political Science Association.; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.).; Social Science Research Council (U.S.).; Stanford University. Department of Political Science. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of Political Science.; Political science--Study and teaching
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1986-047
  - Alumni Correspondence, A, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Correspondence, B, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Correspondence, C, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Correspondence, D, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Correspondence, E, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Correspondence, F, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Correspondence, G, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Correspondence, H, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Correspondence, J, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Correspondence, K, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alumni Correspondence, L, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alumni Correspondence, M, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alumni Correspondence, Mc, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alumni Correspondence, N, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alumni Correspondence, O, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alumni Correspondence, P, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alumni Correspondence, R, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Correspondence, S, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Correspondence, T, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Correspondence, U, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Correspondence, V, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Correspondence, W, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Correspondence, XYZ, 1965-1973, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Letter File, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Letter File, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letter File, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Letter File, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
  - Letter File, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Letter File, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Applicants, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Applicants, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Colleague Recommendations (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Colleague Recommendations, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Student Recommendations, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Student Recommendations, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Student Recommendations, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Successor Search (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Associated Students of Stanford University (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Berkeley-Stanfond Political Development Colloquium (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Blackwell's (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bookstore Corpoation (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - British Government File Make-Up (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - B.R.S. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Camelot (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behaviora1 Sciences (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Center for Central European Studies (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Center for Research in International Studies (CRIS) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Committee on International Studies - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Department of Po1itical Science - Yale University (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Edinburgh Conference (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Graduate Program - Packenham, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Hanover Meeting - October 22-25 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Herring, Pendleton (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Israel (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Issues in the Social Sciences (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Journal of Comparative Politics (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Library, Stanford (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - M.I.T. Visiting Committee (Pamphlets, Bulletins, etc.) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - M.I.T. Visiting Committee Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - M.I.T. Working File (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Meyer Committee (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Movement for a New Congress (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Political Action - IPAG, Levinthal (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Political Science Department, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Admissions Committee (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Political Science Department Policy (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Political Science Department - Faculty Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Political Science Department Course (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Political Science Graduate Student Association (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Political Science Parties (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Princeton University Press to 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Public Events, 1977 Mar-1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Public Events, 1976-1977 Mar (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Stanford Inter-University Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Stanford Studies in Comparative Politics - Series by Stanford University Press (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stanford University Press (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Stanfond University Memoranda (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Studert Evaluation of Courses (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Travel (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Trip to Boston, New York, 1974 May 10-13 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Travel (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tuesday Luncheon Club (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Webbink, Paul (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Weiler, Hans - Central European Studies (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Wood, Bryce (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (AAAS) - Western Center, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Meetinq - May 22 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - General (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Athens Conference (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Western Center, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Membership Meeting, 1972 May 30 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Salk Conference on Urgent Studies, 1970 Mar 20-21 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Committee on Membership (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, pre-1975 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - American Academy of Political ard Social Sciences (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Membership (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Membership Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1976-1986 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Project on the Social Sciences (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Working File (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Working File (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ACAD Nominating Committee (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Proposed Conference on History and Philosophy of Social Sciences (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Flanagan Mundt (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - American Political Science Association - Comittee on Undergraduate Education (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - American Political Science Association (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - American Political Science Association - Panel for 1975 Meetings (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - American Political Science Association - Council Meeting, 1978 Aug 30 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - American Political Science Association (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - American Political Science Review (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Arnerican Sociological Review (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - ACLS - Conference on Political Culture ard Communist Studies, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Counci1 on Foreign Relations - Grayson Kirk (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - HEW (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Humanities and Sciences (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Institute of Political Studies (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - I (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - IPSA Meetings - Munich, August 31-September 4 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Columbia Conference on the Future of International Studies, 1971 Oct (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Krakow Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - National Academy of Sciences (NAS) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - National Academy of Sciences - Newsletters, Pamphlets, etc. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, etc., while at Cambridge, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - National Academy of Sciences - Correspordence (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - National Academy of Sciences - Membership (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Panel for Reviewing Fellowship Applications, 1975 Sept (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - National Humanities Center (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - National Science Foundation Project - Knowledge 2000 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Smelser Conference (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Social Science Research Council - Sponsored Workshop on State ard Nation-building, 1970 Jun 15-Aug 7 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Social Science Research Council - Committee on Comparative Politics (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Social Science Research Council - Comparative Politics (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Social Science Research Council - Committee on Comparative Politics (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Election of New President - Septernber 12-14, Vermont (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Social Science Research Council Forms (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Social Science Research Council - Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Items - Social Science Research Council Publication (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Social Science Research Council Vol. IX (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Social Science Research Council - Committee on Comparative Politics (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Social Science Research Council - Committee on Problems ard Policy (Box 8, Folder 8-10)
  - Studies in Comparative Communism - including Triska Panel (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Access Memo (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Memo on Access (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Social Science Research Council - Sponsored Workshop on State and Nation-building, 1970 Jun 15-Aug 7 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Social Science Research Council Committee on Comparative Politics Meeting - New York Trip, October 22 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Social Science Research Council Fellowships and Grants to be offered in, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Social Science Research Council Trip - March 10 - Washington D.C. Meeting (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Social Science Research Council - Committee on Comparative Politics (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Social Science Research Council Committee Meetings (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
  - Committee on Comparative Politics Meeting, Palo Alto, 1964 Oct (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Social Science Research Council Minutes - Board of Directors (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Government Programs in the Behavioral Sciences (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - ACCESS to Social Science Research Abroad (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - ACCESS to Foreign Areas for Social Science Research (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - ACCESS Material (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Research in Foreign Areas (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Isbell, Eleanor (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - ACCESS Responses (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Testmony before Senate Committee regarding Social Security Restrictions in Developing Areas (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Social Science Research Council - Council on Comparative Politics (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Social Science Research Council - Committee on Comparative Politics (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Western Political Science Association (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Idea of Progress - Background (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Idea of Progress (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Items - Social Science Research Council Newsletter (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Additional Papers, 1939-2001; Accession ARCH-2002-254
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence A, 1991-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence A, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence A, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence B, 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
  - Correspondence C, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence C, 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence D, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence E, 1986, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence F, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence G, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence H, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence J, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence K, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence L, 1989-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence M, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence N-R, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence S, 1987-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence T-V, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence W-Z, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence miscellaneous, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence re William T. R. Fox memorial volume, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence re Larry Diamond, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Paper by Larry Diamond, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Articles by and one letter from Larry Diamond, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Pen Herring, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - National Academy of Arts and Sciences, correspondence etc., 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, American Political Science Association, 1986-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence, American Political Science Association meeting, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, American Political Science Association meeting, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, American Political Science Association meeting, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Merriam Award, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, workshop on case studies in democratization, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Comparative Politics Autobiography, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, papers on David Easton, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, visit to UC Irvine, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, visit to University of Bergen, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Almond's 1945 paper on anti-Nazi opposition in Germany, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Ombudsman work at Stanford, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, CASBS paper, 1988 Nov (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence A, 1990-96 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence C, 1992-97 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence D, 1985-1997 (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
  - Correspondence E, 1989-1997 (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
  - Correspondence F, 1985-1995 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence G, 1991-1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence G, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence H, 1985-1994 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence I, 1990-91 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence J, 1985-96 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Kneuer, Marianne, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence K, 1985-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Correspondence L, 1986-1997 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence Ma, 1985-1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Mc-Me, 1984-1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Mi-Mr, 1987-1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Mu, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence N, 1989-1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence O, 1987-1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence P, 1985-1995 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence R, 1984-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
  - Correspondence Sa-Se, 1986-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Sh, 1985-1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Si, 1986-1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Sm-So, 1985-1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Sp-Ste, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Str-Su, 1985-1994 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence T, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence U, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence V, 1986-1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence V, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence W, 1985-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence X, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Y, 1985-1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Z, 1985-1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Speeches, 1964-1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 1984-1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - David Moses, "How Modern Cardiology and Cardiac Surgery Prevented My Angina from Becoming a Heart Attack" (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Developing Nations Today conference, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Developing Nations Today, Mundt prospect I, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Almond, "Myron Weiner on India and the Theory of Democratization", 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - European Politics Today, 2nd edition, index for (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Comparative Politics Today, reviews and correspondence, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fellowship Forum (Palo Alto), membership lists, 1989, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Political Culture Conference (Irvine, CA) paper, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: publication and symposium on fundamentalism, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Lecture text on fundamentalism, University of North Carolina, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Lecture text on fundamentalism, 1992, with clippings, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Notes and papers (The Fundamentalism Project, AAAS) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - May 1990 meeting - fundamentalism (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Fundamentalism Project [papers and miscellany], 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Fundamentalism Project [papers] A-E (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Fundamentalism Project [papers] F-K (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and miscellany (The Fundamentalism Project) (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
  - Senior Center (Palo Alto) series: Stanford Scholars and Their Work, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, "Return to the State" paper, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1987 Oct-1988 Feb (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
  - Almond, "Political Behavior: Early and Late", 2001 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - G. L. Munck, interview with G. Almond, transcript and note, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - CCC II [Crisis, Choice, and Change Revisited] papers, etc. (Box 10, Folder 1-6)
  - Dorothea Almond Memorial Service (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Dorothea K. Almond Fund for Child Care, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Almond, Richard "'I can do it (all) myself': Omnipotent narcissistic defenses in neurotic patients," draft, 2000 Jul (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Estate matters, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Lecture notes: the State (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes: making of American foreign policy (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes: the confidence gap (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Lecture notes: changes in American political system (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Lecture notes: talk for Fellowship Forum, 1986 Aug 13 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lecture notes: the constitution (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lecture notes: comparative politics, 1985 May 16 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes: history of American political science, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lecture notes: breakdown of authoritarian rule (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Lecture notes: theories in comparative politics, 1985 Sep 25 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Lecture notes: intellectual background of theory of comparative politics, 1977 Jan (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Lecture notes: methodological introductions (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Lecture notes: untitled (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Lecture notes: political good and productivity, 1979 Dec 11 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Lecture notes: Krasner on the state (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Lecture notes: authoritarianism (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Lecture notes: personal rule in Africa (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Lecture notes: political development, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Lecture notes: Packenham and Huntington (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Lecture notes: development theory (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Lecture notes: Wallerstein's world system theory, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Lecture notes: bureaucratic authoritarianism (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Lecture notes: Huntington on authoritarian regimes (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Lecture notes: theory of revolutions (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Lecture notes: Skocpol's theory on revolutions (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Lecture notes: Benjamin Moore (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes: the productive state, 1984 Apr 13 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes: public service/participation (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Lecture notes: history of American political science, 1980 Oct 6 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Lecture notes: Democracy - Dahl's polyarchy (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Lecture notes: types of democracies (Box 12, Folder 6)